Ankit Kumar Roshan

(akr.99799@gmail.com, +91 89497 05320)

Linkedin Github

Overview

Passionate software developer with 2 years of industry experience in building web applications. Involved with the core team in developing and delivering our product. Worked in all phases of product development: definition, design, scoping, planning, implementation, and testing of a new feature.

Work Experience

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer

August 2021 - PRESENT

Skills: Web Development, Reactjs, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Graphql, React-relay, Material-UI, Team Management, Time Management

- Provide Clean and Efficient code review in the team
- Collaborate with internal teams and vendors to fix and improve, implement new features in the product, and create the best possible user experience.
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Researched and optimized code to reduce application latency and increase performance.
- Became an integral part of the core design and development team.
- Helped in developing and delivering multiple products/features to our enterprise clients within the time frame.
- Optimized web accessibility across the application.

Appointy IT PVT LTD, Bhopal — Software Developer Intern

May 2021 - July 2021

Skills: Reactjs, Typescript, GraphQl, Jest, Cypress.io

- Developed a feature that takes the zip code and coordinates of a location and when a customer searches for a zip code it shows the respective location in the search result as well as in Google Maps as a marker.
- Developed and optimized web components.
- Gain experience in unit testing and end-to-end testing of the application to measure its effectiveness.

Skills

- Reactjs
- TypeScript, JavaScript
- HTML, CSS
- GraphQL, React-relay
- Git
- Material-UI, Formik, Yup validation
- Jest, Cypress.io

Education

Vellore Institute Of Technology, Vellore — BTech

July 2017 - July 2021, Vellore

Electronic And Communication

CGPA: 7.8

Personal Achievements

• Covid tracker- https://darling-clafoutis-11f7d4.netlify.app